Arvindkumar Madanlal Gupta



Software (DevOps) Engineer

Mobile no: 9819168754

E-mail: inarvindgupta@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/inarvindgupta.com

Summary: Gained hands-on experience in implementing new infrastructure based on Unix and core DevOps concepts such as containerization, version control, continuous integration, continuous monitoring, continuous deployment etc. Having more than 2 years of experience in it. By using variety of tools and technologies. Drives excellence in every project to deliver outstanding results.

Technical Skills:

- **Cloud Platform** Amazon Web Services **GCP**
- **Databases** MySQL **SQL Server** MongoDB
- CI/CD Jenkins/Bamboo
- Containerization Docker Kubernetes

- **Programming** Languages Java, Python
- **Scripting Language** Bash/Shell Script
- Infrastructure as Code Terraform **AWS Cloud Formation**
- **Source Code** Management GitHub **BitBucket**

- **Source Code Analysis** SonarQube
 - Configuration Management Ansible, Chef
- OS Linux Windows

WORK EXPERIENCE:

Company: <u>Cybage Software Private Limited, Pune (March 2019 – Present).</u>

□ ALM-DevOps Engineer, Project 1: (March 2019 – Present)

Project Description: Creating DevOps Environment infrastructure on multiple projects using tools like Static code analysis tool like SonarQube, Jenkins for Continuous Integration, GitHub and Bitbucket for Source Control Management, Docker for Containerization.

Roles and Responsibilities like:

- Created Terraform for Infrastructure as a Code.
- Static Code Analysis using SonarQube
- AWS Cloud Services like: EC2, S3, VPC, ECS, EKS.
- Created multiple pipelines to implement build, test and deployment of java applications using Jenkins.

- Worked on Docker for Containerization and Kubernetes for Container Orchestration.
- Consultation and/or Making Solution Proposal of Projects for making it CI/CD based.

□ DevOps Engineer, Project 2: (January 2020 – Present)

Project Description: It is an Infrastructure Portal developed in Java Spring boot used by agents to provide a suit of food safety and supply chain solutions.

Roles and Responsibilities:

- Setting up Jenkins as a POD in amazon's EKS (Elastic Kubernetes Service) for high availability.
- Setting up multiple pipeline jobs for microservices.
- Sending auto-alerts through Jenkins jobs.
- Configure Amazon's EFS for Jenkins backup and to store the artifacts of the application.
- Static Code Analysis using SonarQube.

Academics Background:

Education	Board	Result	Year of Passing
PG – CDAC (DAC)	CDAC	First Class	2019
B.E. (Electronics Engineering)	Mumbai University	First Class	2017
Diploma (EXTC)	MSBTE	Distinction	2014
SSC	State Board	Distinction	2011

Professional Certifications:

- "AWS Certified Developer - Associate", done on March-2021.

About me:

Date of Birth:	18 th of February 1995
Gender:	Male
Marital Status	: Unmarried
Nationality:	Indian
Address:	A-wing, 513, Sai Shraddha CHS, VTN Nagar, Chembur, Mumbai-71
Hobbies:	Listening to music, playing: cricket, carrom.